op4g.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy | Op4G | Opinions 4 Good

Effective Date: 4/1/2015 | [Home](http://op4g.com/) >> [Terms of Use](http://op4g.com/terms-of-use/)

This privacy policy applies to [op4g.com](http://www.op4g.com/) owned and operated by Op4G. This privacy policy describes how Op4G collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web sites: [op4g.com,](http://www.op4g.com/) [opinions4good.com](http://opinions4good.com/), and [myop4g.com](http://www.myop4g.com/).  It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Op4G has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program, viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the Web sites and subdomains at [op4g.com](http://www.op4g.com/) and [myop4g.com](http://www.myop4g.com/).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that Op4G have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Security is the key to our shared success. Each element of Op4G is designed to fiercely protect our Members’ privacy and information. We make no distinction between “personal” and “non-personal” information — we protect both equally. And we are 100% transparent with our Members about our policies, their data, and how to safely leave our programs.

Any information conveyed to our Clients is on an anonymous basis, unless specifically approved by a Member through a proactive, opt-in choice.

### Information We Collect

We collect the following personal information from you

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, password

We also collect demographic information from you

  * Date of Birth
  * Gender
  * Marital Status
  * Health Information

We use this information to

  * Send site updates
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Administer targeted surveys

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.  We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending you newsletters. These companies are authorized to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * if Op4G is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets,  you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so
  * Clients are not permitted to directly contact the Op4G membership without company approval. Members’ personal information will never be released to an outside source, except as outlined in our privacy policy or unless legally required as defined in the Op4G privacy policy.
  * Clients are only permitted to interact directly with the Op4G membership through approved and member consented activities. All other Member communications will be through Op4G.

### How do Clients contact Members if follow up is required?

Op4G will oversee and approve all Member and Client communication from start to finish. If a Client requires Member-specific follow up, the member will be notified in the survey invitation if sharing any personal information will be required or optional for participation in the study.

### Secure Databases

Op4G stores personal and survey data in two physically separate server environments. Our data architecture is designed to never allow any Client or third party access to individual member data, or to correlate any data that might identify a participant.

When you enter sensitive information (such as health information) on our forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Member Usernames

Members are assigned a non-traceable unique Op4G username that allows only Op4G to certify the authenticity of information we send to our Clients. Our system is built to prevent the revealing of any individual identity.

### User Access and Choice

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or amend it by making the change on your account information page or by emailing us at support@op4g.com.  We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

### One-Click Account Termination

Want to leave Op4G? A single step of clicking ‘Delete My Account’ on your Account Profile will remove all personal, demographic, and member information from our databases (except for information required by law).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Opt-In Control

Members have total control over what information they receive from Non-Profits. When offered an opportunity to participate in a specific survey opportunity, Members always opt-in and will never be forced to answer or reveal information. If you participate, we will request certain personal information from you. The requested information typically includes information (such as name, age, gender, preferences) and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to __ provide insights into client funded studies associated with a variety of topics.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you.  Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at support@op4g.com.

### Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Op4G and our market research partners, affiliates,  or analytics service providers and affiliate tracking software providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies for our dynamic surveys, to remember users’ settings , language preference or last question answered in surveys, for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve our ability to send relevant surveys to your member account.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/) . Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Links to 3rd party Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Op4G. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

### Blogs/ Forum

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. _To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at_ support@op4g.com.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.  

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements.  With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at support@op4g.com.

### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Op4G stores [or does not store] this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email [and tracking the success of our referral program]. Your friend may contact us at [INSERT URL OR EMAIL ADDRESS] to request that we remove this information from our database.

### No Surprises

Op4G promises to post any changes to our privacy or other policies that affect Member data on our website at least 7 days before making any change. If Op4G intends to have a change in ownership or controlling interest, or if we make any material changes, Members will be notified _by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site  _prior to any change, and can review any policy changes. Members who do not agree with any change can immediately choose to be removed from the Op4G database.

### 100% Transparency

Have a question or concern that we don’t answer on our website? Op4G has a dedicated support team ready to help you. Please contact us through the following:

Op4G  
Corporate Office:  
93 Middle Street in Portsmouth  
New Hampshire, 03801  
603-766-5858
